Hello everyone welcome back to to this another T12 topic. So today here, I'll create for the group by
in the post via SQL and in this group by in the post via SQL allows us to
group row based on the more column and perform the aggregate function on the each group, okay?
And it is probably used in the conjunction with the aggregate function for like the some count average
and etc. So first of all here, I can use the group in row by the single column, okay?
So first of all, just going for here and now just type this template ID. So now it's for
the employee, okay? So now first of all here, just type this select then type for your GMP ID, okay?
And now here use the count function, okay? This complete discount and now just go here,
select from the employee table and now here use the group by
so this is the employee ID, okay? So now here define perfectly and in this way using the group by
plus to group the row from the employee stable by the employee and when it is working the count
function, the count the number of the employee in the each department, okay? So now first of all,
select and then execute. Now you can see here this employee ID is one and here the count is
perfectly one point, okay? So I hope you perfectly understand this. So now going for here another
example that's defined. So here I can use for group in row by multiple column, okay?
So here first of all, I can use for the employee ID and now just here I can define for
just type this with a age column, okay?
And now here all seems here this is the count function for the employee and now just here
add for another column, the age column, okay? So now perfectly use and
here just first by the employee ID column then then by the age column,
then just use the count function to count the number of employees in the each
for employee ID, then the age column, okay? So now just select all and perfectly execute. Now
you can see here the age for 27, 29 perfectly and here this is the all employee ID and this is
the all case for the employee stable, okay? So I hope you understand it. Now here I can use
perfectly just type this is the using for the aggregate function
week for having the cost, okay? So first of all, I can do and type the employee ID.
Now here use for simply just identifying average, okay? So now here just exactly create
and this is the salary column, okay? So now just copy and paste the table and group by for the
employee ID and now here use the having cost the average function and in this inside I can type
for the salary column and now just enter the greater than 50. So now here use the greater than
30,000, okay? So now here define directly create perfectly and here just use for the group by
for the employee table for the ID column and using for the average function to calculate the
average salary for the each department, okay? And having plus filter for the employee for
the average salary, it's greater than 30,000, okay? So now here we have perfectly just
computed and selected all the execute. Now you can see here the key reason for 30,000 for greater
than salary 40,000, 45,000 and 50,000 and last term, okay? So here this session is completely done
and here I can perfectly apply for the group by cross in the post-care skill. So I hope you
perfectly found this tutorial helpful so stay tuned for more interesting important post-care
skill tips and tips, okay? So thank you for watching and happy coding.